rpoints.com 2018-11-24

# Privacy Policy

The purpose of this Privacy Policy is the let you know what type of information we may gather about you, why we collect it, how we use it and the choices you have regarding use of this information. This Privacy Policy needs to be read in conjunction with our [Terms of Use](http://www.rpoints.com/terms-and-conditions.php) and the words and phrases in this page have the same meaning as in our Terms of Use.

About Us

This website is owned and operated by V A C Media Ltd. Registration No. 5512439. We are a UK based company, specialising in operating customer loyalty programs since 2005. 

What Information we collect and why?

We do not collect any more information from you than what is needed for providing our service, improve our service, meet our obligations to you and meet our legal obligations under UK law.

Here is the information we collect and process, with reasons.

  1. Your e-mail address, name/username and password: To help you can register and login to our portal.
  2. Your IP address: To prevent fraud and to ensure your account safety.
  3. Payment details: When you qualify for getting your cashback/reward, we need to be able to pay you. Therefore, we collect payment details (Bank account/other methods) in the secure section our website.
  4. Transactions you make through our website: So we can track your rewards and pay you.
  5. Email/contact preferences (Which you choose in your profile page of our website): This is required so we can email you with service related issues and send newsletters if you consent and choose to get them. 
  6. Contacts you make with us (Customer service tickets or emails or letters you send us): We use this data to provide you with a better service, keep track of issues and train staff.

Storing and Processing Information

We only use the information we collect to improve our website, our customer service and provide you with a better service. We take all necessary measures to keep your data safe and only authorised personnel can access your data. Your data is stored in a secure manner in our UK based data centres.

Where we collect personally identifiable information, we do take extreme care collecting and processing of it. Our members' account area of our site is security encrypted (256-bit Secure Sockets Layer encryption) to high standards.

We do not use any malicious software, adware or malware on our website.

We have procedures to deal with any suspected personal data breach and will notify you and relevant regulators of any such breach. 

Email and Consent

We may contact you by email in the following instances. 

**Account related emails:** These include password changes, service announcements, customer support queries, transactional queries, monthly account statements or relevant changes to our policies. By continuing to use our service you agree to receive such account related emails. 

**Newsletters:** You can choose to opt-in to receive our newsletters by giving your consent in various parts of our website. You can also unsubscribe to our newsletter by selecting the appropriate subscription options in your profile page or by clicking on the "unsubscribe" link at the bottom of our newsletter.

Use of cookies

Our website and our partner merchants' links use cookies. A cookie is a small piece of data or text that is sent from a web server to your browser and is stored on your computer. A cookie can't read data off your computer or read cookie files created by other sites. These cookies do not damage or harm your computer. 

These cookies are essential for making sure you get the cash back for your purchases and for us to improve our website. It is necessary for our members to accept these cookies, as they are essential for the tracking to be able to earn your cashback. By registering to our website and using it, you agree to allow cookies from our website and cookies when you click on our partner retailers. If you do not allow these cookies, some parts of our website and cashback tracking may not work properly for you. We also use google analytics cookies to review usage on our website and its traffic.

If you want to learn more about cookies and how to manage them, you can read the [BBC guide about cookies here](http://www.bbc.co.uk/webwise/guides/about-cookies)

Do we disclose any information to outside parties?

We do not sell, trade, or otherwise transfer to outside parties your personally identifiable information. 

This does not include trusted third parties who assist us in operating our website and servicing you, so long as those parties comply with all relevant EU and UK regulations. We may also release your information when we believe release is appropriate to comply with the law.

Third party Websites

We have partnered with many retailers to enable our members to earn discounts and cashback. When you click on our merchant links, you are taken to the merchant website and make your purchases with the merchant. 

These third-party sites have separate and independent privacy policies. We therefore have no responsibility or liability for the content and activities of these linked sites. Nonetheless, we seek to protect the integrity of our site and welcome any feedback about these sites. 

Data Protection Act & GDPR Compliance

We respect the privacy of all our members and take handling of information seriously. We are voluntarily registered under the UK Data Protection Act 1998 with the Information Commissioner's Office. Registration number: Z918442X.

We also comply with GDPR regulations from the 25th of May 2018.

Your Consent

By using our website, you consent to this Privacy Policy.

Your rights

Under law, you have the right to request access, correction, erasure or object to your personal data being processed or stored. Please contact us if you want to request any of these.

Contacting Us

You can contact us through our online [Helpdesk](http://www.rpoints.com/help/) here.

Our postal address: Customer Care, V A C Media Ltd, 32 North Street, Keighley, West Yorkshire, BD21 3SE.

Changes this Privacy Policy

If we change our privacy policy, we will post those changes on this page and notify you. This policy is updated on 23/05/2018.
